welcome back this is category five
dobrodošli nazad ovo je kategorija pet
technology TV Sasha do you remember when
Tehnologija TV Sasha se sjećate kada
we tried to pilot a new show called try
pokušali smo probati novu emisiju koja se zove probati
it buy it that was a fun one episode
kupio je to je bila jedna zabavna epizoda
instead it was so much fun
umjesto toga bilo je toliko zabavno
depending on where you're located in
ovisno o tome gdje se nalazite
this big ol world of ours
ovaj naš veliki svet
you may remember it as either the Sega
možda je sećate kao Sege
Mega Drive or the Sega Genesis and now
Mega Drive ili Sega Genesis i sada
more than a quarter of a century after
više od četvrt veka kasnije
its original release in Japan it's more
originalno izdanje u Japanu je više
convenient than ever to take these
zgodan nego ikada da ove
classic Sega games with you my review is
klasični Sega igre s vama moj pregled je
coming right up so stick around try it
Ide pravo tako ostati probati
[Music]
[Music] \ t
Sega Genesis portable unit and it has
Sega Genesis prijenosna jedinica i ima
it's got it's got the works
dobio je posao
it has ton no man like if you want to
nema ni jednog čoveka kao što želite
play Sonic the Hedgehog it's it's there
igraj Sonic the Hedgehog to je tamo
can you all see that classic right so
Možete li svi da vidite tako klasično pravo
this is the portable that you reviewed I
ovo je prenosni koji ste pregledali
had to bring it out because tonight is a
morao sam ga izvesti jer je večeras
little bit of a retro gaming throwback
malo retro retro igre
and bear with me I'll be a little while
i podnesi sa mnom malo vremena
one of the things that was really cool
jedna od stvari koja je bila stvarno cool
about this though this device is not
o tome iako ovaj uređaj nije
only does it have a built in screen but
samo da ima ugrađen ekran, ali
it also has an adapter that you can plug
takođe ima adapter koji možete priključiti
into the jack and now you can plug it
u utičnicu, a sada ga možete priključiti
into your standard old TV set right
u vaš standardni televizor
perfect with the RCA right right but no
savršeno sa RCA desnim pravom ali ne
HDMI output so it doesn't work on a
HDMI izlaz tako da ne radi na
modern TV unless it has a VN which a lot
moderni TV osim ako nema VN koji je mnogo
of them do so we were still pretty good
od njih smo i dalje bili prilično dobri
to play this up on the big screen I
igrati ovu se na velikom ekranu I
think you plugged it into your 60-inch
mislim da ste ga uključili u vaš 60-inčni
TV and tried it out so did you know that
TV i isprobali ga, jesi li to znala
the Raspberry Pi also supports this
Raspberry Pi takođe podržava ovo
cable so if you plug this into the
kabl, pa ako ga priključite u
headphone jack of the Raspberry Pi it
priključak za slušalice od Raspberry Pi je
automatically detects it and senses it
automatski ga detektuje i oseti
and says oh that's not headphones that'd
i kaže oh to nije slušalice koje bih
be an RCA cable let's switch over to AV
biti RCA kabel prebaciti na AV
mode so now the the Raspberry Pi works
tako da sada Raspberry Pi radi
on a standard old-style CRT TV now that
sada na standardnom CRT televizoru
I bring to your attention because there
Donosim vašu pažnju jer tamo
is no more ultimate retro gaming
nije više ultimativna retro igra
experience than sticking it up on a 22
iskustvo nego da ga zabijem na 22
inch
inch
CRT TV right you gotta admit that's
CRT TV pravo morate priznati da je to
retro right that is right child what
retro pravo je pravo dete šta
else would be super retro oh I want to
drugo bi bilo super retro , hoću
tell you all about it I can't wait to
sve o tome ne mogu da dočekam
show you the case that we're looking at
vam pokazati slučaju da gledamo
tonight but first of all we took it to
večeras, ali pre svega to smo uzeli
the next level on episode number 442
sljedeći nivo na epizodi broj 442
because we're so into retro gaming and
jer smo u retro igra i
so we sat down and we built the first
pa smo sjeli i napravili prvi
retropie that we had ever built it is
retropie da smo ikada izgrađen je
lovely and it works great and they're
divno i to odlično radi i oni su
still using that so you guys are still
još uvek koristiš to, pa vi momci ste još uvek
enjoying this plugged in by HDMI yeah on
uživajući u ovom priključku HDMI-ja da
a 60-inch TV now this is a Raspberry Pi
60-inčni TV sada je ovo Raspberry Pi
3 now I lied a little bit this wasn't
Sada sam malo lagao da nije
the first retropie we built because we
prva retropija koju smo izgradili jer smo mi
tried it on a Raspberry Pi 2 first okay
pokušao sam na Raspberry Pi 2 prvo dobro
then you bought the Raspberry Pi 3 for
onda ste kupili Raspberry Pi 3 za
the upgrade and it has run fantastically
nadogradnja i pokrenut je fantastično
well but there was one thing that didn't
ali bilo je nešto što nije
run well do you remember what that was
dobro se snalazite da li se sećate šta je to bilo
putting on the spot there was a
stavljanje na licu mjesta bilo je
particular system that's built into the
određeni sistem koji je ugrađen u
retro pie and I retropie there were some
retro pita i ja retropija bilo je nekih
games that didn't work in the n64 yes
igre koje nisu radile u n64 da
the Nintendo 64 was like yes copy yeah
Nintendo 64 je bio kao da kopiraj da
No so unplayable basically what a retro
U suštini ne može se reprodukovati ono što je retro
pie is and you can go back to episode
pita je i možete se vratiti u epizodu
number 442 if you want a retro throwback
broj 442 ako želite retro povratak
but what it is now it's a distribution
ali ono što je sada to je distribucija
of Linux that goes on to the micro SD
Linuxa koji ide na mikro SD
card on your Raspberry Pi microcomputer
karticu na vašem mikro računaru Raspberry Pi
so it's like this small and you can put
tako da je ovako mali i možete staviti
any number of game roms on there it's of
bilo koji broj igara za igru ​​na njemu
course like a Nintendo Entertainment
naravno kao Nintendo Entertainment
System Sega Genesis a KA Master System
Sistem Sega Genesis a KA Master sistem
Atari Atari 2600 7800 Lynx it's got it's
Atari Atari 2600 7800 Lynx to mora da je to
got everything and then it does have the
ima sve, a onda ga ima u
n64 it's got Sony Playstation the
n64 ima Sony Playstation
original yeah which does play very well
originalni yeah koji se igra jako dobro
surprisingly and and all kinds of
iznenađujuće i svih vrsta
support we're gonna look at it in just a
Podrška ćemo pogledati u samo a
couple minutes time one of the neat
par minuta vremena jedan od urednih
things about it to Sasha if you want to
stvari o tome Saši ako želite
hold up your controller how do you
držite kontroler kako vam odgovara
control it I can drill it with this with
kontrolišem ga i mogu ga bušiti sa ovim
a ps3 remote yep because the Raspberry
ps3 daljinski yep jer je malina
Pi 3 has built-in bluetooth so we're
Pi 3 ima ugrađeni bluetooth pa smo mi
able to use that
sposoban da to iskoristi
and sync it to the the Raspberry Pi and
i sinhronizuj ga sa Raspberry Pi i
it becomes a controller for the retropie
postaje kontroler za retropiju
is what it's called because that's the
ono što se zove, jer je to
distribution of raspbian that that we
raspodela raspjana da smo mi
put on it and it's got emulators out the
stavi ga i ima emulatore
wazoo and everything else I use an Xbox
wazoo i sve ostalo koristim Xbox
controller I don't know if it's is this
Kontroler Ne znam da li je ovo
an Xbox one or Xbox 360 controller I
Xbox ili Xbox 360 kontroler I
don't know I picked it up at a used game
ne znam da sam ga pokupio u korištenoj igri
shop and it is not bluetooth so I had to
shop i nije bluetooth pa sam morao
pick up this little guy here off of
pokupi ovog malog ovde
Amazon it was like 14 bucks nine bucks
Amazon je imao 14 dolara za 9 dolara
something like that and it's just USB to
nešto tako i to je samo USB
receiver for the Microsoft controllers
prijemnik za Microsoft kontrolere
oh that's perfect yeah so retro gaming
O, to je savršeno da, tako retro igranje
is it's funny that retro gaming has come
smešno je što je retro igranje došlo
so far in the past couple of years
do sada u proteklih nekoliko godina
because now retropie the distro has
jer sada retropija distro ima
brought up version 4.4 so what's new
dovela je verziju 4.4, pa šta je novo
with 4.4 boy well let's say what's new
sa 4.4 momkom dobro recimo šta je novo
with the Raspberry Pi let's just say the
sa Raspberry Pi recimo samo
B+ how's that so the the new Raspberry
B + kako je to nova malina
Pi 3 model b+ it came out and it's 1.4
Pi 3 model b + je izašao i on je 1.4
gigahertz processor it's got its more
Gigahertz procesor ima više
powerful it's faster it runs cooler and
Moćniji je brži i hladniji
theoretically it should be able to run
teoretski bi trebalo da bude u stanju da radi
our emulators better than the original
naši emulatori bolji od originala
Raspberry Pi 3 which clocks out as caps
Raspberry Pi 3 koji radi kao kape
out at 1.2 gigahertz and when it gets
na 1.2 gigaherca i kada se pojavi
warm it clocks down to 900 megahertz
zagrijavaju satove na 900 megaherca
like 0.9 gigahertz so this one's a lot
kao 0,9 gigaherca tako da je ovaj dosta
faster the Raspberry Pi 3 B plus so the
brže Raspberry Pi 3 B plus tako
4.4 release of retropie introduces
4.4 uvođenje retropije
support for the Raspberry Pi 3 B+ that's
podrška za Raspberry Pi 3 B + to je
what we're excited about now it also
i ono što smo sada uzbuđeni
brought in now not the image the image
sada nije donio sliku slike
file can only be burnt to a Raspberry Pi
Datoteka se može spaliti samo na Raspberry Pi
card so you can only move it from a
karticu tako da je možete premjestiti samo iz a
Raspberry Pi however they've also put a
Raspberry Pi, međutim, oni su takođe stavili a
lot of effort into creating scripts to
mnogo napora u kreiranju skripti
allow you to install retropie on other
omogućuju vam da instalirate retropie na drugom
platforms so you know the Odroid xu4 q
platforme tako da znate Odroid xu4 q
that i have is a super powerful 8 core
koje imam je super moćno 8 jezgre
SBC it's available on that it's
SBC je dostupan na tome
available on the c 1 c 2 x u 2x u 3x u 4
dostupno na c 1 c 2 x u 2x u 3x u 4
I don't
Ne znam
it's like all the Oh droids but then the
to je kao i svi Oh droidi, ali onda
new version brings out the SU stinker
Nova verzija donosi iz SU smrdljivac
board support as well so if you're a
podršku za ploče, pa ako ste vi
tinker board tinkerer then rudimentary
Tinker board tinkerer onda rudimentaran
support for that now as well through the
podršku za to sada i kroz
scripting of that so performance is
skriptiranje te tako performanse
meant to be a lot better on the
značilo je da bude mnogo bolje na
Raspberry Pi 3 B+ now because it's got a
Raspberry Pi 3 B + sada jer ima a
better processor we're gonna put that to
bolji procesor ćemo staviti to
the test tonight when we launched our
test večeras kada smo pokrenuli naš
Nintendo 64 stuff shall we look at how
Nintendo 64 stvari ćemo pogledati kako
we obtained retropie we shall first of
dobili smo retropiju
all back it up a little bit how to get a
sve napravite ga malo kako da biste dobili
PI a Raspberry Pi go to cat 5 dot TV
PI Raspberry Pi idite na cat 5 dot TV
slash PI as I move this stuff around I
slash PI pomicanja ove stvari oko I
so badly want to show you what our retro
tako jako želim da vam pokažem šta je naš retro
pie looks like decide we're gonna take a
pita izgleda kao da ćemo odlučiti
look at that in just a couple of minutes
pogledajte to za samo nekoliko minuta
time okay so I'm gonna bring up retro
vreme je u redu pa ću da pozovem retro
pie now we talked about Raspberry Pi
sad smo razgovarali o Raspberry Pi
we're used to p i rights but it's
smo navikli pi prava, ali to je
actually pi like they took it one step
zapravo, pi kao da su to učinili jedan korak
further and said no no this is the
dalje i rekao ne ne ovo je
edible and so let's bring it up on my
jestiva i zato je pokažimo na mojoj
screen
screen
retro pie this is a weird one dot org
Retro pita ovo je čudna jedna tačka org
dot uk' not co dot uk' dot org dot uk'
dot uk 'nije co dot uk' dot dot dot '
that's gonna bring you here tells you
to će te dovesti ovamo
all about retro pi and again so you buy
sve o retro pi i opet tako da kupite
the Raspberry Pi unit and put it
Raspberry Pi jedinicu i stavi je
together in whatever case you want make
zajedno u bilo kom slučaju koji želite
it you know however you want tonight
to znate koliko želite večeras
we're taking it to the next level of
vodimo ga na sljedeću razinu
retro Ness with a very retro case but
retro Ness sa vrlo retro slučajem, ali
you don't have to do that you can just
ne moraš to da radiš
use the stock case that comes with the
Koristite stock slučaj koji dolazi sa
kit if you like but here retro pie is
kit ako vam se sviđa ali ovdje je retro pita
the distribution that we're gonna use so
distribucija koju ćemo koristiti
you don't on a Raspberry Pi you don't
ne radite na Raspberry Pi-ju
have to install raspy inner noobs and
morati instalirati raspy unutarnje noobs i
then install retropie that's a real
zatim instalirajte retropie koji je pravi
roundabout way to do it it can be quite
zaobilaznim putem to može biti sasvim
onerous so what you can do instead is
tegoban tako što možete učiniti umjesto toga
just download the complete image it's
samo preuzeli kompletnu sliku je
ready to go it's ready to deploy you
spreman da krene, spreman je da vas rasporedi
just boot it up and it's done so that's
samo ga podignite i to je učinjeno
what I'm gonna show you tonight real
ono što ću ti pokazati večeras
briefly so you can see retropie version
ukratko kako biste mogli vidjeti retropie verziju
4.4 was released April 14th 2018 with
4.4 je objavljen 14. aprila 2018. godine
all of the bonuses that we mentioned and
sve bonuse koje smo pomenuli i
we've got support for the zero
imamo podršku za nulu
the one which you know I don't know how
onaj za koji znate da ne znam kako
the gaming would be on there maybe NES
igranje bi bilo tamo možda NES
classic would be fantastic but certainly
klasik bi bio fantastičan, ali svakako
the the Atari stuff and then there's
Atari stvari i onda tu je
these supported the Raspberry Pi 2 and 3
oni su podržavali Raspberry Pi 2 i 3
which includes the B+ so when you click
koja uključuje B + tako da kada kliknete
on that it's going to download you an
na to će vas preuzeti
image dot GZ file so if you're on
slika dotaknite GZ datoteku pa ako ste uključeni
Microsoft Windows you're going to need a
Microsoft Windows će vam trebati
program called 7-zip in order to to
program pod nazivom 7-zip kako bi se na
extract that file because you need the
izvadite tu datoteku jer vam je potrebna
image file if you're on Linux or Mac OS
slikovnu datoteku ako ste na Linux ili Mac OS
you're going to be able to extract that
moći ćete to izvući
just by right-clicking on it and go
samo desnim klikom na nju i idite
extract her here something like that
ekstrakt je ovde tako nešto
so once you've downloaded that now
pa kad ste preuzeli da je sada
here's where some folks actually you
evo gde su neki ljudi zapravo vi
know find this a little bit almost
znam da je ovo skoro skoro
confusing because you know what how do I
zbunjujuće, jer znate kako ja
install this now I've I've got my SD
instalirajte ovo sada imam svoj SD
card and I've copied that image file on
i kopirao sam tu sliku
to it and I don't understand why it
i ne razumem zašto
won't boot and that's because we
neće se dizati i to je zato što mi
remember how we used to have to boot
zapamtite kako smo nekada morali da dignemo
burn CDs yes when you burned a CD then
snimite CD-e da kada ste onda snimili CD
you could boot it but you had to burn it
možeš ga pokrenete, ali si morao spaliti
using special software that would create
koristeći specijalni softver koji bi stvorio
the boot loaders and everything else so
boot utovarivači i sve ostalo tako
same thing goes for your SD card it's
ista stvar vrijedi i za vašu SD karticu
actually a very similar process but
zapravo vrlo sličan proces
we're gonna use a program that is freely
Koristićemo program koji je slobodan
available and all this stuff is free
sve to je besplatno
other than the hardware but we're gonna
osim hardvera ali ćemo
go to at your dot i/o and when we go
idite na vašu tačku i / o i kada idemo
there this is available on Windows Mac
tamo je to dostupno na Windows Mac-u
and Linux and you're gonna download this
i Linux i to ćete preuzeti
program and just follow the prompts nice
program i samo pratite lijepe upute
and simple there it is for Windows Mac
i jednostavno tu je za Windows Mac
and Linux this is a great tool for
i Linux za ovo je odličan alat
burning your stuff and I say burning we
gori tvoje stvari i ja kažem da gori
still use that term even though and that
još uvek koristim taj izraz iako i to
comes from the laser that's edging into
dolazi od laser koji je ivica u
a write there's no real burnin you're
pisanje nema prave Burnin si
not actually burning your but the term
zapravo ne spaljujemo vaš, već pojam
still exists and and it still applies so
još uvijek postoji i još uvijek vrijedi
so what you do is you you then browse to
Dakle, ono što radite je onda pregledavati u
the image that you downloaded this is a
slika koju ste preuzeli je a
screenshot here so with select image you
screenshot ovdje tako da sa odabranom slikom
browse to the image then you plug in
potražite sliku i uključite je
your SD card for your Raspberry Pi and
svoju SD karticu za Raspberry Pi i
it will automatically select it and then
automatski će ga odabrati i onda
you hit flash and just make sure that
pritisnete bljesak i samo se uvjerite
that second step that you have indeed
taj drugi korak koji ste zaista imali
selected the correct card it's probably
izabran ispravan karticu verovatno je
best I always recommend unplug all your
najbolje preporučujem da isključite sve
like USB flash drives and everything
kao USB flash diskovi i sve ostalo
else before you do this because you
drugo pre nego što to uradite, jer vi
wouldn't want to accidentally overwrite
ne bi htio slučajno prepisati
the wrong exactly that way there's no
pogriješio upravo na taj način nema
messing around you
zezati oko tebe
exactly what it is exactly I would do
tačno šta bih tačno uradio
the wrong thing first no no now I would
pogrešna stvar prvo ne, ne sada bih
do the right thing and I want to show
uradi pravu stvar i želim da pokažem
you everything else that we've got to
sve ostalo što imamo
show you here so that shows you a little
pokazaću vam ovde da vam pokaže malo
bit about how to get this
malo o tome kako da ovo dobijem
that's retropie get four point four or
to je retropija dobiti četiri točke četiri ili
higher when we come back I'm going to
više kad se vratimo idem
show you what I think is probably the
pokazati vam ono što mislim da je vjerojatno
ultimate retro geek case for the retro
ultimate retro geek kućište za retro
pie system because we got a totally
sistem pite jer smo dobili totalno
retro it out right you get out this
ako ga izvučemo iz pravca, izvadite ovo
suspense oh don't go anywhere whether
neizvjesnost oh ne idi bilo gdje da li
you shop on think geek gearbest B&amp;H
kupujete na think geek gearbest BiH
Photo Video eBay or Amazon or even if
Foto Video eBay ili Amazon ili čak i ako
you want a free trial of audible you'll
želite besplatnu probnu zvučnih ćete
find the best deals and support the
pronađite najbolje ponude i podršku
shows we produce by simply visiting the
pokazuje da proizvodimo jednostavno posjetom
shopping sites you already frequent by
shopping web stranice koje su već često po
using the links on our website visit
pomoću linkova na našoj web stranici posjeti
category-five TV slash partners for the
kategorije pet televizijskih partnera za
full and ever-growing list and help us
punu i stalno rastuću listu i pomozite nam
create more free content like this show
stvorite više besplatnog sadržaja kao što je ova emisija
thank you for shopping with our partners
hvala vam za kupovinu sa našim partnerima
and thank you for watching welcome back
i hvala vam za gledanje dobrodošao natrag
this is category 5 technology TV tonight
ovo je tehnologija TV kategorije 5 večeras
is retro gaming night and that's because
je retro gaming noć i to je zato
retropie 4.4 has been released with
Retropija 4.4 je objavljena sa
support for the Raspberry Pi 3 model b+
podrška za Raspberry Pi 3 model b +
tonight we're going to put it to the
večeras ćemo ga staviti na
test we're gonna fire it up live on the
testiraćemo da ćemo ga ispaliti uživo
show and the rest of the show is just
show i ostatak predstave je pravedan
gonna be us playing super mario bros so
će nam se igra super mario bros tako
first of all if you want to get yourself
prije svega ako želite doći do sebe
a really cool retro case for your retro
stvarno zgodan retro slučaj za tvoj retro
pie head on over to cat 5 dot TV slash
pita glavu na na mačka 5 dot TV slash
hi are you ready for this yes ok first
hi jeste li spremni za ovo da ok prvi
of all with my brand new Raspberry Pi 3
sve sa mojom novom Raspberry Pi 3
B+ the first thing I want to do is I
B + prva stvar koju želim da uradim je ja
want to put
Želim da stavi
heatsinks on it now these are available
Heatsinks na njemu sada su dostupni
on Amazon you can grab heatsinks they
na Amazonu možete uzeti heatsink
probably know in my case they came with
verovatno znam u mom slučaju da su došli
the the kit that I bought from Kanna ket
komplet koji sam kupio od Kanne ket
so cat5 got TV /pha you buy the kit it
tako da je cat5 dobio TV / pha da kupiš komplet
comes with heatsinks so I need to put on
dolazi sa hladnjacima, tako da moram obući
the CPU heatsink just to keep that nice
hladnjak CPU-a samo da bi to bilo lijepo
and cool that's going to dissipate the
i kul to će raspršiti
the heat even better than the the
vrućina je čak i bolja od
improved cooling kind of metal cover
poboljšana vrsta hlađenja metalnog poklopca
that's on the Raspberry Pi 3 B+ and then
to je na Raspberry Pi 3 B + i onda
there's one for this little chip over
postoji jedan za ovaj mali čip
here I don't know if that's the math
ovde ne znam da li je to matematika
coprocessor - I'm not sure what that is
koprocesor - Nisam siguran šta je to
but it's cute and this will keep it cool
ali to je slatko i ovo će ga održati hladnim
because it does get hot real simple
zato što se stvarno zagreva
there's stickers you don't need any
ima nalepnica koje ti ne trebaju
frosting or anything like that
glazura ili nešto slično
yep just push down on it a little bit
Yep samo malo pritisnuti na to malo
give it a little bit of pressure and now
da je to vrlo malo pritiska i sada
we are ready to install it in our new
spremni smo ga instalirati u naš novi
retro case and this ladies and gentlemen
retro slučaj i ove dame i gospodo
is just the box they went all out and I
je samo kutija koju su svi izašli i ja
I would pay somebody I would ask them
Platio bih nekome koga bih pitao
how can I send you money just to buy
kako vam mogu poslati novac samo da kupite
that box and inside the box is is really
ta kutija i unutar kutije je stvarno
what it's all about folks and we talked
to je sve o ljudima i razgovarali smo
about mini game systems like the mini
o mini igraćim sistemima kao što je mini
and like the SNES mini and look at this
i kao SNES mini i pogledajte ovo
a Nintendo Entertainment System
Nintendo Entertainment System
miniaturized it's got USB and Ethernet
minijaturno, ima USB i Ethernet
there it's got HDMI port on the back the
tu je HDMI port na poleđini
SD card and there incidentally on the
SD kartica i tamo slučajno na
bottom here where there normally was the
ovde gde je normalno bio
GPIO or the connection is a little
GPIO ili veza je malo
storage case they even got that detail
skladišni slučaj čak imaju i taj detalj
to put your SD cards in it's got two USB
da stavite SD kartice u njega ima dva USB
ports on the front and a working power
priključke na prednjoj strani i radnu snagu
button that operates just like the
dugme koje radi baš kao i
original NES like it holds in it's not
originalni NSZ kao što drži u njemu nije
like just a momentary switch it stays in
kao trenutni prekidač ostaje
it came with a fan as well the
je došao sa ventilatorom kao i
screwdriver some screws and just a quick
odvijač vijaka i samo brzo
little instruction set look at that if
mali set instrukcija gleda na to ako
we need to okay so we're gonna actually
Moramo u redu, tako da ćemo zapravo
put this together for you tonight so
Stavite ovo zajedno za vas večeras
let's let's get started
hajde da počnemo
cool I guess the fan is just gonna
cool Valjda ventilator je samo da
offset draw some of the heat out of
offset izvući neke od topline iz
there and there's some screws to mount
tamo i ima vijaka za montiranje
that to the case so what I like about
da je slučaj tako što volim
this if you notice the USB ports on the
ovo ako primetite USB portove na
front and everything and they it
i sve to i oni
actually has circuitry like it's not
zapravo ima kola kao da nije
your typical Raspberry Pi case that you
Vaš tipični slučaj Raspberry Pi
just stick the PI in and then plug
samo ubacite PI i uključite
everything into the PI it has these
sve u PI ima ove
connectors that plug into the PI and
konektori koji se priključuju na PI i
then it has its own headers that make it
onda ima svoje sopstvene zaglavlje koje ga čine
so that you're not restricted to the
tako da niste ograničeni na
form factor of the pie itself so with my
oblik faktora same pite tako sa mojim
Raspberry Pi 3 B+ I'm just going to
Raspberry Pi 3 B + Ja ću samo
insert that with the HDMI at the back
umetnite ga sa HDMI priključkom sa zadnje strane
but first we'll connect in Ethernet and
ali prvo ćemo se povezati u Ethernet i
that will make live the Ethernet port on
koji će živjeti Ethernet port
the front of the what's called an S PI
prednje strane ono što se zove S PI
case plus so this is the next generation
plus plus ovo je sledeća generacija
of the nest PI case and this one is
slučaja gnezda PI, a ovaj je
slightly larger than the original with
nešto veći od originalnog sa
better cooling and a little bit more
bolje hlađenje i malo više
airflow and certainly less cramped and I
protok vazduha i svakako manje skučen i ja
think it looks more legitimately like a
mislim da izgleda legitimnije kao a
real Nintendo Entertainment System than
pravi Nintendo Entertainment System od
the original case so it just kind of
originalni slučaj, tako da je samo vrsta
goes in there just line up the headers
ulazi tamo samo poravnati zaglavlja
at the back because it is going to
pozadi jer će se to desiti
you're gonna plug your HDMI directly
direktno ćete priključiti HDMI
into the PI and then we've just got a
u PI i onda smo upravo dobili
little pack of screws most of those six
malo čavlića većine tih šest
of those are for the case itself because
od toga su za sam slučaj, jer
this is a case that we're gonna assemble
ovo je slučaj koji ćemo skupiti
and leave assembled it's not something
i ostavite okupljenu, to nije nešto
you're going to be swapping your board
zamenićeš svoj odbor
in and out of but then there are two
unutra i van, ali onda postoje dva
screws to actually mount the Raspberry
vijci za montiranje maline
Pi board to this case now keep in mind
Pi ploča za ovaj slučaj sada imajte na umu
this is compatible with B model boards
ovo je kompatibilno sa modelima B modela
so you're looking at the Raspberry Pi
tako da gledate Raspberry Pi
two Raspberry Pi three Raspberry Pi
dva Raspberry Pi tri Raspberry Pi
three model B+
tri modela B +
so you can you can mount other system
tako da možete montirati drugi sistem
boards in here as well and presumably
i ovdje i pretpostavljam
future-ready as as well as long as the
spreman za budućnost, kao i koliko dugo
form factor on the new raspberry PI's
faktor na novom PI malinama
stay the same so with these two screws
Ostanite isti sa ova dva vijka
it's just going to mount that in C and I
to će se samo montirati na C i I
have to make interesting Sascha we're
morati napraviti zanimljiv Sascha smo
putting in two screws so you're doing a
stavljanje u dva vijka tako da radiš
great job thanks
odličan posao hvala
tiny tiny screws yeah look at how tiny
sićušni sićušni vijci, da pogledate koliko su sitni
they are they're tinier than a pie
one su manje od pite
everything on the pie is so cute oh this
sve na pita je tako sladak oh ovo
is just the cutest no it's nice and snug
je samo najslađi nije lijepo i udobno
it feels real snug there you go
osećam se kao da ste u pravu
now this header here is gonna give you
sada će ti ovo zaglavlje dati
the fan so we just plug that it make
ventilator tako da ga jednostavno priključimo
sure you put it in the right way the the
Sigurno ste ga stavili na pravi način
pins are on the outside of the Raspberry
igle su na vanjskoj strani maline
Pi and that enables the header on the
Pi i koji omogućava zaglavlju na
top there and gives it power for the fan
tamo gore i daje mu snagu za ventilator
as well as whatever other power is
kao i bilo koja druga moć
needed now there's no designator here
sada je potrebno da nema oznake
which way the fan is blowing I know from
na koji način je ventilator duva znam iz
experience that usually the the sticker
iskustvo koje obično naljepnice
side is where it's going to be blowing
strana je tamo gde će puhati
out of so I'm gonna put that down so
tako da ću to tako staviti dolje
that we're drawing the heat out of the
da izvlačimo toplotu iz
case we're not gonna be drawing air into
u slučaju da nećemo ulaziti u vazduh
it we want to push the air out of it and
želimo da izbacimo vazduh iz njega i
it just snaps in there and then there
samo se ugura tamo i onda tamo
are three screws that that just hold the
su tri vijka koja samo drže
fan in place so it's not going to fall
ventilator na mjestu tako da neće pasti
out
out
some good TV right here folks riveting
neki dobri TV-i ovde, ljudi koji zakivaju
look at that
pogledaj to
look at the way I turned the screw and
pogledaj kako sam okrenuo vijak i
and note the screwdriver was even
i zapamtite da je odvijač bio ravan
included so I didn't even have to buy
uključen tako da nisam ni morao kupiti
buy or find a tiny enough screwdriver
kupite ili nađite dovoljno mali odvijač
it's it's included so now you've got an
to je to tako da sada imam uključen
extra screwdriver for that's actually
dodatni odvijač za to je zapravo
very considerate yeah you know until you
veoma obazriv, da, znaš, dok ne dođeš
end up with with 300 of these
završiti sa 300 od njih
screwdrivers you're happy that they
odvijači ste sretni što su oni
included it yeah now you can also fix
uključio ga da sada možete popraviti
glasses I feel like I'm thinking that
naočare Osjećam se kao da razmišljam o tome
this is gonna be a perfect size for
za ovo će biti savršena veličina
changing motors in my drone oh that's
menjajući motore u mojoj dronji
perfect nice simple installation folks I
savršen lijepo jednostavna instalacija ljudi I
think if you give yourself ten minutes
razmislite ako sebi date deset minuta
time now we're not going to take that
sada nećemo to uzeti
much time tonight because I have the
Mnogo vremena večeras jer imam
power to accelerate the video a little
moć da malo ubrza video
bit but ten minutes time is all you need
malo, ali deset minuta je sve što vam je potrebno
and then you're gonna be up and running
i onda ćeš biti gore i trčati
with your retro pie so I'm not sure
sa tvojim retro pitama, tako da nisam siguran
which way to to put this cable on to the
na koji način staviti ovaj kabl na
this is the fan header I'm not sure
ovo je zaglavlje ventilatora nisam siguran
which way it goes and there's no like
kojim putem ide i nema sličnog
one way you can put it on either way I
jedan način možete staviti na bilo koji način
don't see anything in the instructions
ne vidim ništa u uputstvima
about the fan either it's only about the
o ventilator ili je to samo o
case and the installation of the pie so
slučaj i instalacija pite tako
I could plug it in with the positive on
Mogao bih da ga priključite sa pozitivnim na
the left and you can always change the
levo i uvek možete da promenite
polarity and that's going to change the
polaritet i to će promeniti
direction of the fan but actually the
pravac ventilatora, ali zapravo
the red
crveno
I'm just looking and there is a marking
Samo gledam i postoji oznaka
that says the positive is on the right
to kaže da je pozitivno na desnoj strani
my right so that should be the correct
moje pravo da to bude tačno
way to put that fan in there okay so now
tako da stavite taj ventilator tamo dobro
the next step is just to close it up and
sledeći korak je da ga zatvorimo i
I'm just I'm making sure that the cable
Samo sam ja vodeći računa da kabel
there is not gonna there's a quite a bit
neće biti dosta
of slack on that cable I don't want it
olabaviti taj kabl, ne želim ga
to obstruct the fan I don't want it to
ometati ventilator koji ne želim
get into the fan I guess I could put a
uđite u ventilator, pretpostavljam da mogu da stavim
twist tie on that or something like that
izokrenuti vezu ili nešto slično
but I think it looks like it's gonna
ali mislim da izgleda kao da ce
stay out of the way it's not gonna nudge
Drži se dalje od načina na koji to neće gurati
its way over to the fan so shouldn't be
njegov put do ventilatora ne bi trebao biti
a problem
problem
and that should just snap right together
i to bi trebalo samo da uskoči
there we go doesn't that look awesome
tamo idemo ne izgledaju sjajno
oh my goodness I can't wait to show this
Bože, ne mogu dočekati da ovo pokažem
to my family because we grew up with
mojoj porodici jer smo odrasli
that look at the SD card slot on the
da pogledate slot za SD karticu na
side - all right so now we've got those
strana - u redu, sada ih imamo
six screws we've got to put in this is
šest vijaka koje moramo staviti u ovo
where you know this is this is way too
gdje znate da je ovo tako
much for you so I'm gonna speed this up
Mnogo za tebe pa ću ubrzati
a little bit what was your first retro
malo ono što je bio tvoj prvi retro
gaming system Sasha growing up I played
igrački sistem Sasha odrastao sam igrao
well I played Atari games and then I had
dobro sam igrao Atari igre i onda sam imao
I think I skipped right - Super Nintendo
Mislim da sam preskočio pravo - Super Nintendo
really to be honest you went from Atari
stvarno da budem iskren ste otišli iz Atari
2600 to a Super Nintendo yeah I had an
2600 na Super Nintendo da sam imao
Atari 2600 and then when the NES came
Atari 2600, a onda kada je došla NSZ
out so the Atari 2600 was like when I
tako da je Atari 2600 bio kao kad sam ja
was born mm-hmm and then I got the
je rođen mm-hmm i onda sam dobio
Nintendo Entertainment System when it
Nintendo Entertainment System kada je to
came out so there it is folks so this
izašla tako da je ljudi tako da je ova
really is a throwback for me
Za mene je stvarno povratak
I'm so proud and excited about this just
Tako sam ponosan i uzbuđen zbog ovo samo
this case that's gonna sit under our TV
Ovaj slučaj će biti pod našim TV-om
in full sight
u punom pogledu
it's got HDMI on the back you'll notice
ima HDMI na poleđini koju ćete primetiti
that the header for the power has been
da je zaglavlje za moć bilo
offset using their built-in header and
offset pomoću ugrađenog zaglavlja i
it looks astonishing it is sharp it is
izgleda zapanjujuće je oštar je
so cool the ultimate retropie retropie
tako kul krajnja retropija
case and there it is are we ready to
slučaj i to je to smo spremni
fire this out yes we are all right it
otpustiti ovo da smo svi u pravu
feels good I you know people are gonna
prija Znam te će ljudi
ask like is it flimsy and cheap no it
pitam kao da je to slaba i jeftina
feels like substantial it feels real
oseća se kao da je suštinski, oseća se stvarno
solid it is solid and you feel that
čvrsto je i čvrsto i vi to osjećate
button yeah it's click click click click
dugme da to je klik kliknite na klik
yeah momentary so it's just like the
Da, trenutno je tako kao
original and I guess you know folks are
original i pretpostavljam da znate da su ljudi
wondering about the SD card slot over
pitate se za slot za SD karticu
here so there it is I've already put in
Evo, dakle, tu sam već stavio
our retropie SD slot card and it just it
naš retropie SD slot karticu i to je upravo to
goes in and out nice and easy it's not
ulazi i izlazi lepo i lako nije
gonna fall out there you go there we go
ispasti tamo i ti idemo tamo
ok so let's fire it up sash all right
ok pa hajde da je upaliti krila sve u redu
here we go now I can plug in power
sada idemo sada mogu da uključim struju
because remember it has a power poor
jer zapamtite da ima siromašnu moć
power button on the front it's not going
dugme za napajanje na prednjoj strani ne ide
to turn on until I hit that button
da upalim dok ne pritisnem to dugme
I'm gonna go HDMI output so it supports
Idem HDMI izlaz tako da podržava
HDMI but it does have access to the the
HDMI ali ima pristup u
AV port as well so if you want you can
AV port , tako da ako želite možete
use one of these cables right and plug
koristite jedan od ovih kablova desno i utikač
that in here and then you've got RCA
To ovde i onda imate RCA
output for an old-style TV right or if
izlaz za staro TV pravo ili ako
you're real retro want to go completely
ti si prava retro želiš da ideš potpuno
retro absolutely okay and then I
retro apsolutno u redu i onda ja
mentioned a little bit earlier that I'm
pomenuo sam malo ranije da sam ja
using an Xbox controller so I do need to
koristeći Xbox kontroler pa moram
use an Xbox receiver because it's not
koristite Xbox prijemnik zato što nije
bluetooth if we wanted to we could use
bluetooth ako želimo da smo mogli koristiti
Sony Playstation three remote switch our
Sony Playstation tri daljinski prekidač naš
Bluetooth and then I would not need a
Bluetooth i onda mi ne treba a
receiver and I could play it just like
prijemnik i mogao sam igrati baš kao i
that so no no extra wires coming out of
da tako ne bez dodatnih žice koje izlaze iz
the front I think that would be cool so
prednji Mislim da bi tako bilo cool
I'm gonna get myself some PlayStation
Doneću sebi PlayStation
controllers but it does have two USB
ali ima dva USB
ports on the front two and then another
porta na prednjoj strani dva, a zatim još jedan
two under here so but you see the ones
Dva ovde ispod, ali vidite one
there you can plug those that you can
tamo možete uključiti one koje možete
get USB retro NES controllers that look
dobiti USB retro NES kontroleri koji izgledaju
exactly like the originals but their USB
baš kao i originali, ali njihov USB
anyway that is that's the next that's if
u svakom slučaju to je da se u narednih to je ako
you're completely obsessed with retro
potpuno ste opsednuti retro
okay so I'm gonna plug in my receiver
U redu, uključiću svoj prijemnik
here and I'm just gonna push the power
ovde i samo ću gurnuti snagu
button there it goes and just so you
Tamo se kreće i samo tako ti
know she's a Putin and I can feel that
znam da je Putin i mogu osjetiti da
there is wind coming out of the top of
tu je vjetar izlazi iz vrha
the retropie so you went in the right
retropija, tako da ste otišli u desno
direction so I did go in the right
pravac tako da sam išao na desno
direction and the correct polarity there
pravac i pravilan polaritet tamo
it is
TO JE
and ladies and gentlemen retropie is
i dame i gospodo je retropija
booting on our Raspberry Pi 3 model D
dizanje na naš Raspberry Pi 3 model D
plus in an NES PI case plus case I'm
plus u slučaju NES PI plus slučaj
just gonna leave this running all the
Samo da napusti ovaj radi sve
time connect it to my TV what it just
vreme je povezati sa mojim TV-om što je upravo
reminds me so much I just already
podseća me toliko da sam već
player1 the movie yes and in the mood I
player1 film da i u raspoloženju I
don't know if you've seen the movie yet
ne znam da li ste još videli film
no I have not I feel like you should
Ne, ne osećam se kao da bi trebalo
okay
U redu
but in it the creator of the Oasis which
ali u njemu je stvoritelj Oaze koja
is the virtual reality alternate
je alternativna virtualna stvarnost
universe that everybody lives in and
svemir u kome svi žive i
plays in but the creator of it was very
igra u, ali stvaralac je bio vrlo
obsessed with retro games oh yeah so all
opsednuta retro igrama oh da tako sve
of the little Easter eggs and everything
malih uskršnjih jaja i svega
in the Acura it's all
u Acuri je sve
oh so there you go you ready to jump in
oh tako si spreman za skok
if yes ready player one yeah okay so no
ako je spreman igrač jedan da, u redu, tako ne
game pads detected so on my xbox
igraći jastučići otkriveni su na mom xboxu
controller I just holding the power
Upravljač sam samo držao struju
button just like I was connecting to an
dugme kao što sam se povezivao sa
Xbox and it will and then I press a and
Xbox i to će i onda ću pritisnuti a i
there I am so welcome to version 4.4 of
tamo sam tako dobrodošao u verziju 4.4 od
retro pie so we've got Atari 2600 Atari
retro pita, tako da imamo Atari 2600 Atari
2070 eight hundred links mega drive
2070 osam stotina linkova mega disk
which is the plate the oh now I'm why do
što je ploča oh sada sam zašto
they name them differently what do we
oni ih drugačije nazivaju što mi
call it the Genesis Genesis Genesis here
nazovite ga Genesis Genesis Genesis
in the western world that's the one that
u zapadnom svetu to je onaj koji
we we had a Genesis growing up as well
mi smo imali Genesis odrastanja, kao i
Nintendo 64 Nintendo Entertainment
Nintendo 64 Nintendo Zabava
System
Sistem
I feel honor bound being that we are
Osećam da je vezan za čast da jesmo
running in an NES kit to click on words
trčanje u NES kompletu da klikne na reči
I support this decision do you know
Podržavam ovu odluku znaš
again
opet
I played NES with my grandma and you'll
Igrao sam NES sa svojom bakom i ti bi
notice see how it says unknown at the
uočite kako piše nepoznato
right that's because this is a fresh
to je zato što je ovo sveže
install and I have not synced all the
instalirajte i nisam sinhronizovao sve
artwork yet now it will go out onto the
umjetnička djela, ali sada će izići na
internet and get all the graphics the
internet i dobiti sve grafike
covers the reviews the description of
pokriva recenzije opisa
every game but we have not yet done that
svaka utakmica, ali to još nismo uradili
you can do that should we like to skip
to možete uraditi ako želite preskočiti
down to like Super Mario Bros I believe
verujem u Super Mario Bros
so yes all right
tako da, u redu
oh and the chat room seems to agree
oh i soba za ćaskanje izgleda da se slaže
Super Mario says tollbooth yeah okay
Super Mario kaže da je u redu
I'll get there I'll get there amazing
Stići ću tamo i doći ću tamo
okay Oh what did I do
U redu, šta sam uradio
I've clicked right sorry I jumped into
Kliknula sam pravo žao mi je što sam skočila
PlayStation Nintendo Entertainment
PlayStation Nintendo Entertainment
System
Sistem
[Music]
[Music] \ t
super super mario bros okay now you'll
super super mario bros sada dobro
notice it says two twice cuz I think I
primijetiti piše dva puta jer sam da sam
selected the wrong artwork oh one of
izabrao pogrešnu ilustraciju o jednom od
these is Super Mario Bros one and one of
ovo je Super Mario Bros jedan i jedan
them is Super Mario Bros 2 do you think
mislite da je to Super Mario Bros 2
the first one is right let's try it yeah
prva je prava, hajde da probamo
okay don't press anything here folks
U redu, ne pritiskajte ništa ovde
oh I got it I got it okay and it's
Oh, dobio sam ga
widescreen it is so cool oh my goodness
widescreen je tako cool oh moj Bože
did it didn't do now I don't think I
se to nije učinio sada ne mislim da
have I don't think I have audio piping
da ne mislim da imam audio cev
out from the retropie right now but
sada iz retropije, ali
there you have it
to je to
Oh see my phone ring oh yeah Mario
Oh vidi moj telefon zvoni oh yeah Mario
Brothers yeah
Brothers yeah
so I am literally right now playing
tako da sam doslovno upravo sada sviram
Super Mario Bros on an Xbox controller
Super Mario Bros na Xbox kontroleru
on mini nes over here now if I press
na mini je sada ovdje ako pritisnem
Start and select at the same time that
Pokrenite i odaberite istovremeno
gets me back to the main menu right okay
što me nazad na glavni meni pravo dobro
so now I can go I can go back with B and
tako da sada mogu da idem sa B i
now I can scroll over to other systems
sada mogu da pređem na druge sisteme
and see what I want to do so we had
i da vidim šta ja želim da uradimo
talked about the Nintendo 64 being poor
govorili su o tome da je Nintendo 64 siromašan
performance on retropie in the past yeah
performans na retropiju u prošlosti yeah
mine Mario Kart was like good good good
moj Mario Kart je bio dobar dobar dobar
good good good not worth it couldn't do
dobro dobro dobro nije vredno toga
it and I think Mario Kart is probably a
i mislim da je Mario Kart verovatno a
really good test everybody wants to play
stvarno dobar test svi žele igrati
Mario Kart every day all the time so
Mario Kart svaki dan sve vrijeme tako
let's let's go there it's fine now just
hajdemo tamo, sada je dobro
for the record retropie is an operating
za snimanje retropija je operativni
system for your retro gaming system
sistem za vaš retro gaming sistem
raspberry pi it does not come with any
malina pi ne dolazi s bilo kojim
games okay so the games you you have to
igre u redu tako da igre morate
find them you might find abandoned ware
nađite ih možete naći napuštene robe
which is you know software that's so old
što znate o starom softveru
that presumably it's free yeah
koji vjerojatno to je besplatno da
they don't sell it anymore yeah
više ga ne prodaju
companies companies are starting to do
kompanije koje počinju da rade
this where they're bringing back out
tamo gde vraćaju
retro games so that they can rebirth the
retro igre, tako da mogu ponovno rođenje
copyrights on those games
autorska prava na te igre
oh and so it's a little bit ah so do it
oh i tako je malo ah to uradi
now so just keep that in mind so you are
sada to imajte na umu tako da jeste
not gonna see all these games on there
neće videti sve te igre tamo
out of the box it's gonna be empty
Iz kutije će biti prazno
you'll need to get those yourself where
morat ćete ih sami odvesti gdje
am I headed
ja sam na čelu
yeah Mario Kart yes oh no I need to go
da Mario Kart da oh ne moram ići
out yeah I'm going the wrong way here I
da , idem na pogrešan način
skipped over it while I was talking okay
preskočio sam je dok sam govorio u redu
Mario Mario Mario Mario Mario Mario Kart
Mario Mario Mario Mario Mario Mario
64 okay this is literally a moment of
U redu, ovo je doslovno trenutak
truth
istina
we've tried running this before and it
Pokušali smo da ga pokrenemo i ranije
was so stuttery that you could not play
bio je tako mucan da se ne možeš igrati
it right let's see how smooth you are
da vidimo kako ste glatki
let's see how smooth we are again we
da vidimo kako smo opet glatki
don't push anything during this because
nemojte ništa gurati tokom ovoga jer
that's gonna customize your controls
to će prilagoditi vaše kontrole
which I don't want to I want to leave
što ja ne želim da želim napustiti
everything like as defaults I've done
sve kao što sam uradio
that have you accidentally and then got
koje ste slučajno i onda dobili
stuck and had to restart it I don't even
zaglavi i morao je da ga ponovo pokrenuli ja i ne
understand okay that screen did not fly
razumem dobro da ekran ne leti
like that it looks so good oh and like
kao da izgleda tako dobro oh i kao
I'm pushing the start button on my
Guram dugme za pokretanje na mom
controller I wish I had a second game
Želim da imam drugu igru
controller here for you Sasha but what
kontroler ovde za vas Sasha ali šta
I'll do is I'll start the game and let
Ja ću početi igru ​​i pustiti
you drive I feel like that's been a bad
voziš se osećam kao da je to loše
idea have you seen me drive this is this
da ste me videli da vozim ovo je ovo
doesn't end well ever okay you start
ne završava se dobro kad počneš
okay 150cc
okay 150cc
okay here we go
U redu, idemo
Luigi do we want mushroom cup flower Cup
Luigi želimo gljiva kup cvijet Cup
star Cup or special Cup special Cup yeah
star Cup ili posebni kup specijalni kup da
oh oh and I think I could have I could
oh oh i mislim da sam mogao
have actually chosen a track underneath
su zapravo izabrali stazu ispod
it's been a long time Sasha the
Prošlo je dugo vremena Sasha
performance so far is out of this world
učinak do sada je izvan ovog svijeta
like I'm hard-pressed to think I'm not
kao da mi je teško da mislim da nisam
playing on a Nintendo 64 let's see how
igranje na Nintendo 64 da vidimo kako
it performs in game oh oh it's not leg
on igra u igri oh oh to nije noga
Yahweh okay so Robbie sucks bye
Jahve u redu tako Robbie sranje bye
I'd say this actually plays as well as I
Rekao bih da je to zapravo igra tako dobro kao ja
sweat oh do you yeah and this place as
znoj oh, da li ti i ovo mesto kao
well as yours I think South $400.00
kao i tvoja, mislim da je $ 400.00
switch it just ruffle my pack just
prebacite ga samo razbacajte moj paket
rumbled it has haptic feedback no way
tutnjao ima povratne informacije ni na koji način
that's cool
to je kul
sorry I got a little excited there I did
Žao mi je što malo uzbuđen tu jesam
not realize it even had that how do I
nisam shvatio da je čak imao i to kako
get out of here
izlazi odavde
oh no I am stuck forever I got excited
oh ne , zauvek sam zapeo
and I crashed into a wall uh-oh
i udario sam u zid uh-oh
come on Robbie you're an eighth-place
Dođi na Robbie, ti si osmo mesto
come on man how do I back up is there a
hajde čoveče, kako da se vratim tamo, a
reverse no you can reverse the camera
obrnuto ne možete preokrenuti kameru
yeah oh come on no it can't go down like
da oh, ne, ne može da padne kao
that what we can my it's yeah we'll just
da ono što mi možemo, to je da, mi ćemo samo
we'll speed it up for you
ubrzat ćemo za vas
yeah the performance is great they're
Da, predstava je sjajna
gonna be just matching into that wall
biću samo uparivanje u taj zid
yeah I'm serious how do I backup Sasha
Da, ozbiljan sam kako da poduprem Sašu
oh oh thank you did you buy pressed why
oh oh hvala ti si kupio pritisnuo zašto
okay I'm on it
u redu sam na tome
remember I'm on an Xbox controller and
Zapamtite da sam na Xbox kontroleru i
I'm terrible but look at that
Strašno sam, ali pogledajte to
performance folks I love that that is
ljudi iz performansa Volim to
exquisite I'm gonna jump to a larger
Izuzetno ću skočiti na veći
screen for you folks at home I'm gonna
ekran za narode kod kuće cu
give that to you I don't know that
dati da vam ja to ne znam
that's the best choice okay okay I found
to je najbolji izbor u redu u redu sam našao
B B is to like make it go okay
BB je kao da je u redu
controller is your left analog okay
kontroler je vaš lijevi analogni u redu
remember everyone I ride a bike I don't
sećam se da ne vozim bicikl
drive a car 150cc little Mario Kart so
voziti auto 150cc mali Mario Kart tako
far I haven't seen any lag
daleko nisam video nikakvo zaostajanje
chat room what do you think so far oh
chat room što mislite do sada oh
yeah we got paperboy come on all the
Da smo se Paperboy hajde sve
classics oh I'm in the wrong eyes you're
klasici oh, ja sam u pogrešnim očima
going the wrong way sighs okay okay it's
ići pogrešnim putem uzdiše u redu to je
cuz okay I still I'm goin the wrong way
jer u redu ja još uvijek idem pogrešnim putem
I thought I did reverse what's happening
Mislio sam da sam preokrenuo ono što se dešava
okay I know we have to go to the news
U redu , znam da moramo da idemo na vesti
room soon I would rather just play this
uskoro bih radije samo svirala
you know this could be the show folks ah
znate ovo bi mogao biti u emisiji ljudi ah
there we go
Evo idemo
Oh see it's not all me I'm not I'm not
Oh, vidi da nije sve što ja nisam, nisam
it's it's difficult it's challenging
to je teško da je izazov
because we haven't played in so long
jer nismo dugo igrali
folks head on over the cap five dot TV
Ljudi prelaze preko pet tačaka na TV
/pi get your gear and then hook yourself
/ pi nabavite opremu i onda se zakačite
up with retropie 4.4 and I'm
sa retropijom 4.4 i ja sam
flabbergasted i anytime we do a feature
ošamućen sam kad god napravimo značajku
like this on the show it's like how is
ovako na show-u to je kako je
it going to perform is it gonna is this
to će se desiti ako je ovo ovo
gonna be impressive or is it gonna be
će biti impresivno ili će biti
disappointing or is it gonna crash
razočaravajuće ili će se srušiti
what's the opposite of a flop this is
ono što je suprotno od flop ovo je
the opposite is like the ultimate Oh
suprotno je kao krajnji Oh
amazing like this is going to be the
neverovatno kao što će ovo biti
best gift you buy whomever you love
najbolji poklon koji kupite koga volite
Sasha my kids are going to adore this
Saša moja deca će ovo obožavati
see and this sitting on under the TV
vidite i ovo sedite ispod televizora
like when I have family over and we all
kao kad imam porodicu i svi smo
grew up with the Nintendo Entertainment
odrastao sa Nintendo Entertainment
System that's amazing and it's not
Sistem je neverovatan i nije
overly expensive either I mean we're so
previše skupa, mislim da smo tako
cost you know raspberry pie kit all the
košta znate malina pita kit sve
all the peripherals SD card power cable
sve periferije SD kabl za napajanje
the board itself the heat sinks you're
sama ploča vas grije
looking about a hundred dollars Canadian
gleda oko sto dolara kanadskog
70 $79 us kind of idea and in this case
70 $ 79 smo mi ideja i u ovom slučaju
is like 25 bucks Canadian so that's like
je kao 25 ​​dolara kanadski tako da je to
four dollars u.s. it's not a huge
četiri dolara za nas to nije ogromno
investment but as you can see we can
investicija, ali kao što možete vidjeti u našoj moći
load it up chock full of games and it is
napunite ga punom igara i to je
still a Raspberry Pi so keep that in
još uvek Raspberry Pi tako da zadržite to unutra
mind because you can install other
umu jer možete instalirati druge
things on it you can pack it as a full
stvari na njemu možete spakovati kao punu
computer if you just want the retro look
kompjuter ako samo želite retro izgled
and you want to use a wireless keyboard
i želite koristiti bežičnu tipkovnicu
and mouse and turn it into your home
i miša i pretvorite ga u vaš dom
theater PC
pozorište PC
or use it as a computer you can do that
ili ga koristite kao kompjuter koji to možete da uradite
that would just throw everybody off that
to bi samo odbacilo sve
you actually would be awesome
ti bi stvarno bio strašan
that is the retro pie gaming system
to je sistem za igranje retro kolača
version 4.4 from cat5 TV slash pie
verzija 4.4 od cat5 TV slash pie
[Music]
[Music] \ t
[Applause]
[Aplauz]